Robert Huff Papers
Robert Huff Papers
1947-1966
Huff, Robert, 1924-
0.5 linear ft.
Papers of the American poet. Manuscript and published poems; published material by and about Huff.
149065
Biographical History
Robert Huff (1924-1993) was an American poet. He studied at Wayne State University, where he received his B.A. (1949) and his M.A. (1952) degrees. He taught at the University of Oregon, Fresno State College, and Oregon State College, and was an associate professor of English and a Poet in Residence at the University of Delaware. Mr. Huff's poems appeared in The Paris Review, Harper's, The Atlantic Monthly, The Saturday Review and Poetry, and he authored a volume of verse entitled Colonel Jackson's Ride and Other Poems, (1959).
Scope and Contents of the Collection
The Robert Huff Papers consist of biographical material, correspondence, a subject file, manuscripts and published material.
Biographical material contains biographical data released by The University News magazine of Indiana University. Correspondence includes incoming correspondence from various notables in the field of poetry and one outgoing piece of mail. The single Subject file consists of a promotion sheet for a scheduled reading of Huff's poetry by Huff. Manuscripts contains poems by Huff. Published material includes a newspaper article about Huff and his poems and the published poems of Huff and others.
Arrangement of the Collection
Correspondence is divided into incoming (arranged alphabetically by sender) and outgoing. Manuscripts are arranged alphabetically by the title of the poem as it appears in the final draft. Poems are arranged as to whether they appear in a magazine of verse or singly as clippings. They are divided further alphabetically according to the title of the poem.
Subject and Genre Headings
Literature -- American Poetry; Huff, Robert, 1924-; American poetry -- 20th century.; Poets, American.; Drafts (documents); Poems.; Poets.
Access Restrictions
The majority of our archival and manuscript collections are housed offsite and require advanced notice for retrieval. Researchers are encouraged to contact us in advance concerning the collection material they wish to access for their research.
Inventory
- Correspondence
  - Incoming
    - Booth, Philip (Xerox copy), 1961 (Box 1)
    - C, H, W (2 Xerox copies), 1957; 1958,; 1964 (Box 1)
    - Ciardi, John, 1964 (Box 1)
    - e.e. cummings (Xerox copies with explanatory notes by Huff), 1948-1949; 1951-1952,; 1960-1962,; undated (Box 1)
    - Engle, Paul (Xerox copies), 1956 (Box 1)
    - Hecht, Anthony (Xerox copies), 1958 (Box 1)
    - Morehouse, Marion (Mrs. e.e. cummings) (Xerox copy), undated (Box 1)
    - O'Faolain, Sean (Xerox copy), 1964 (Box 1)
    - Roethke, Theodore (Xerox copy), 1961 (Box 1)
  - Outgoing
    - 1965 (Box 1)
- Subject file
  - Promotion for scheduled reading by Huff, undated (Box 1)
- Manuscripts
  - Poems
    - "Between Wars", 1965; worksheet and final draft (Box 1)
    - "Fred's Case", 1965; worksheets (Box 1)
    - "My Tomboy's Doggerel", 1966; worksheets (Box 1)
    - "Old Astronauts", undated; worksheets and final draft (Box 1)
    - "On Hearing of the Death of Bernard Strempek", 1965; worksheet and final draft (Box 1)
    - "Passing Through", undated; typescript (Box 1)
    - "September, 1966", worksheets and final draft (Box 1)
    - "Spirit Duck", undated; worksheets and final drafts (Box 1)
    - "With Robert Frost at Boiler Bay", undated; typescript and final draft (Box 1)
- Published material
  - Newspaper clippings
    - About The Cardinal, 1963 (Box 1)
  - Poems by
    - The Atlantic Monthly, 1950; 1954,; 1956,; 1958 (Box 1)
    - Harper's, 1947; 1948 (Box 1)
    - N W R (North Western Review ?), undated (Box 1)
    - Panorama, 1950 (Box 1)
    - The Paris Review, 1958 (Box 1)
    - Poetry, 1950 (Box 1)
  - Poems by Huff and Others
    - Folio, 1958 (Box 1)
    - Milestone 1, 1949 (Box 1)
    - Milestone 2, 1949 (Box 1)
    - Milestone 3, 1950 (Box 1)
    - Milestone 4, undated (Box 1)
    - Poetry Northwest, 1959 (Box 1)
    - Venture, 1963 (Box 1)
    - Voices, 1955 (Box 1)
    - Voices, 1963 (Box 1)